Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 688 records 1916-1993 IBT0038
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Local 688 records
1916-1993
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0038
1.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains material produced by and about IBT Local 688 which operated out of St. Louis, Missouri. It includes material from Local 611 which also operated out of St. Louis. The material is dated from 1916-1993. The material includes meeting minutes, the "Midwest Labor News" newspaper, photographs, and a dissertation focused on the history of Local 688. The material documents portions of the career of Harold Gibbons, a leader within the Teamsters and the broader American labor movement during his career.
Arrangement
This collection is organized alphabetically.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains material produced by and about International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 688 from St. Louis, MO and related unions dating from 1916-1993. Included are meeting minutes, the "Midwest Labor News" newspaper, photographs, and a dissertation focused on the history of Local 688.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by International Brotherhood of Teamsters 2012 [2012.086].
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor; Labor unions; Labor and laboring classes; Labor unions -- Missouri -- History -- 20th century; Gibbons, Harold J., 1910-1982
- "An Experiment in Trade Union Democracy: Harold Gibbons and the Formation of Teamsters Local 688, 1937-1957", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  Author: Lon W. Smith.
- CIO, scrapbook and "Co-Op" Magazine", February 1947-April 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "The Crucial 70's: Labor's Stake" Officers' Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Harold Gibbons newsclippings, miscellanous, November 1972-May 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Harold J. Gibbons Offices and Appointments (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Harold Gibbons newsclippings, St. Louis Globe-Democrat, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Harold Gibbons newsclippings, St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Harold Gibbons story-"St. Louis Weekly-'The Socialist Teamster'.", July 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- IBT Local 611 Meeting Minutes, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- IBT Local 611 Meeting Minutes, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- IBT Local 611 Meeting Minutes, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Labor Press Associates-Ben Dor column, July 26, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellanous CIO newsclippings, October 1947-May 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Midwest Labor World" Newspaper, 1956 July 1 - 1957 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- "Midwest Labor World" Newspaper, 1957 June 1 - 1958 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- "Midwest Labor World" Newspaper, 1958 July 1 - 1960 January (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "Missouri Teamster" Newspaper [1], May 16, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Further reference
  For more "Missouri Teamster" newspapers, see IBT 0031-Box 2-Folder 11.
- "Missouri Teamster" Newspaper [2], August 15, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Further Reference
- "Missouri Teamster" Newspaper [3], October, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- "Missouri Teamster" Newspaper [4], November 21, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographs, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Teamsters Local 688 Health and Medical Camp Guide Book, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  There are three versions of the Local 688 Health and Medical Camp Guide Book dating from 1970-71. One has notations written within it.
- Teamsters Local 688 Health and Medical Camp Report, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Meeting, 1975 October 9 (Box 3, Cassette 1)
- Contract, 1975 December (Box 3, Cassette 2)
- March 1976, 1976 March (Box 3, Cassette 3)
- Meeting, 1976 March 11 (Box 3, Cassette 4)
- Spec Reg Meeting, 1976 April 8 (Box 3, Cassette 5)
- Local #6 Meeting, 1976 May 13 (Box 3, Cassette 6)
- Union Meeting, 1976 May 13 (Box 3, Cassette 7)
- Meeting, 1976 June 10 (Box 3, Cassette 8)
- Meeting, 1976 June 10 (Box 3, Cassette 9)
- Local #6 Meeting, 1976 November 11 (Box 3, Cassette 10)
- November 11, 1976, 1976 November 11 (Box 3, Cassette 11)
- Contract, 1976 December 4 (Box 3, Cassette 12)
- Union Meeting, 1976 December 9 (Box 3, Cassette 13)
- Spec Nominating Meeting, 1977 January 20 (Box 3, Cassette 14)
- February 10, 1977, 1977 February 10 (Box 3, Cassette 15)
- Local #6 Meeting, 1977 February 10 (Box 3, Cassette 16)
- March 10, 1977, 1977 March 10 (Box 3, Cassette 17)
- Cassette: Local #6 Meeting, 1977 April (Box 3, Cassette 18)
- Union Meeting, 1977 May 12 (Box 3, Cassette 19)
- June 9, 1977, 1977 June 9 (Box 3, Cassette 20)
- Special Meeting, 1977 June 21 (Box 3, Cassette 21)
- #23, undated (Box 3, Cassette 22)
- National Strike, A.B. Brew House Gate, No. 1, undated (Box 3, Cassette 23)
- National Strike, A.B. Brew House Gate, No. 2, undated (Box 3, Cassette 24)